Register of the Joseph C. Trainor papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Supreme Commander for the Allied Powers (SCAP). General Headquarters (GHQ). Civil Information and Education Section (CIE) File, 1943-1952
  - Education Division
    - Directives to the Japanese Government
      - By number, selected directives from 93 to 1944
    - Dissolution of branch offices. Study, 1949 November 19
    - Education Committee Report, undated
    - Education Division library. Memo, 1951 April 5
    - Education Finance, Chapter IX
    - Education for War. Research report, 1946 March - 1948 October
    - Education in Japan
      - General, 1947-1951 (Box 22)
      - Bibliography, circa 1951
      - Education in Japan. Informational handbook, 1946 February 15
      - Legislation, statistics and other materials pertaining to Tokyo, 1950 August
    - Education in the New Japan, Vol. II, 1948 May
    - Education Ministry Administrative Inspection Committee Report, 1948 March
    - Education Mission Plans for 1949. Report, draft, 1949 February
    - Education, moral, 1946-1951 (Box 23)
    - Education of the Deaf in Japan, by Oosima-Isao. Reprint, 1950 September
    - Education plans - New curriculum, 1946-1950
    - Education reform - General
      - 1945-1949
      - undated
    - Education research card catalog - Subject headings, 1947 September
    - Education Research Institute (Kyoiku Kenshujo), principles of, 1946 July
    - Education steering committees. Memo, 1946 August 17
    - Educational minimum standards law, 1949-1951
    - Educational planning committees, undated
    - Ehime Military Government Team - Report on board of education, 1948 October 14
    - Elementary education
      - 1937-1945
      - 1946-1951 (Box 24)
    - Engineering education. Report, 1951
    - Evaluation of the magazine Truth (Shinso), 1950 March 17
    - Evans, Lloyd L. (Chogoku Regional Education Officer) - Letters of appreciation to, 1952
    - Experimental schools, 1949
    - Explanation of Short-Course University Standards. Report, 1949 October 6
    - Explanation of State Department's Organization and Function in Japan. Memo, 1951 October 5
    - Faculty lists, undated
    - Field trips
      - 1946 January - May
      - 1946 September - 1947 November
      - 1947 December - 1948 February (Box 25)
      - 1948 March - April
      - 1948 May - June 18
      - 1948 June 19 - July
      - 1948 August - September
      - 1948 October - 1949 January (Box 26)
      - 1949 February - October
      - 1949 November - 1950 March
      - 1950 April - May
      - 1950 June - July
      - 1950 August - December (Box 27)
      - 1951 January - May
      - 1951 June
      - 1951 July
      - 1951 August - October
      - 1951 November - December
      - Plans for 1952 (Box 28)
    - Finance, 1947-1950
    - Foreign teachers, 1948 March - May
    - Forestry education program. Report, 1950 February
    - Forestry schools, 1949
    - Fryklund, Verne C. (consultant on vocational teacher training). Report, 1948 August 6
    - Functions of the Education Division, 1946-1951
    - The Fundamental Causes of Japan's Defeats, undated
    - Fundamental education law
      - 1946
      - 1947-1951
    - General View of Education for the Handicapped Children in Japan, by Unosuke Kawamoto, undated
    - Girl Scout organizations, 1948-1949
    - Guidance and Welfare Institute, 1950-1951
    - Guidance training project. Memoranda, 1951
    - Gumma-Ken secondary school teachers' union - General rules and convention, 1947 May 27 (Box 29)
    - Health and Physical Education, Report on Status of Courses in Fields of, 1949 August 22
    - Health and Physical Education, Chapter IV
    - Higher education
      - 1946-1947
      - 1948
      - 1949-1951
      - undated
    - Higher education in the rehabilitation of Japan, program of committee on, undated (Box 30)
    - Historical articles on the war in the Pacific, 1931-1945
    - Historical Background of Japanese School Curriculum, by Dr. Kataro Tanaka, undated
    - The History of Democracy in Japan, by H. E. Norman, undated
    - The History of Japanese Education. Report, undated
    - History of non-military activities of the occupation of Japan, 1945-1950
    - History of Students' Ideological Movements (English translation), 1949-1950
    - Hokkaido Board of Education election, 1950 September - November
    - Home economics courses. Memo, 1947 March 31
    - Human rights. Memo, 1950 November 15
    - Hyogo prefecture agricultural college, school catalog, 1951 April
    - Imperial rescripts on education, 1945-1951
    - Imperial rescripts and ordinances. Study, 1945 November 27 (Box 31)
    - Improvement of Educational Personnel in Service, Chapter XII
    - Inspection of offices, undated
    - Institute for Educational Leadership, Chapter X
    - Institute for Educational Leadership (IFEL)
      - General.
        - 1948 March - December
        - 1949 January - December
        - 1950-1951
        - 1951-1952
        - undated
      - Reports
        - 1949
        - 1950 (Box 32)
        - 1950-1951
    - Institute for Educational Research, 1947-1948
    - Institute for Students' Guidance and Welfare, undated
    - Inter-library loans. Memo, 1947 December 16
    - Inventory to files, undated
    - Investigation of Persons Physically Defective. Report and memoranda, 1946 June - July
    - An Investigation of Teachers: Cost of Living. Report, undated
    - Japan Education Association (Nippon Kyoiku-kai)
      - 1942-1946
      - 1947-1948
      - undated
    - Japan Educational Workers' Union. Clipping, undated
    - Japan Society for Promoting Education, 1946 February
    - Japan's New Educational System, by the American Council on Education. Outline of pamphlet to be published, undated
    - Japanese Education Committee
      - General, 1946
      - Recommendations, undated
    - Japanese Education Reform Committee (JERC)
      - General
        - 1946 (Box 33)
        - 1947
        - 1948
        - 1949-1951
        - undated
      - Candidates, undated
      - Members, 1946 (Box 34)
      - Reports, 1946 December
    - Japanese history courses
      - Kuni No Ayumi, for 6th grade elementary school. Typescript, undated
      - Readings in Japanese history, undated
      - Wartime history for elementary school, Vol. B, grade 6. Typescript, 1944 April 28
    - Japanese Language Council, 1945-1951
    - Japanese National Leaders Project, 1950-1951
    - Japanese school system, 1945-1947
    - Japanese teachers' unions
      - 1945 (Box 35)
      - 1946
      - 1947
      - 1948
      - 1949-1951
      - undated
      - Budget, 1949 (Box 36)
      - Collective agreement. Original draft, 1947 August 9
      - Collective contracts, interpretation of, undated
      - Draft of talk to be given at teachers' convention, 1947 October 15
      - Teachers' salaries, 1946 November, 1949 January
      - White Paper on Education, 1950 April 14
    - Japanese travel outside Japan, 1949
    - Japanese University Accreditation Standard Association
      - Educational standards of various departments in university education. Report, 1951 June 21
      - Reorganization of higher education in Japan, undated
      - Report No. 5, Part III: Educational Standards for Homemaking, undated
      - University standards. Typescripts, 1949 February 28, 1950 June 13
    - Japanese who have attended United Nations conferences. List, 1950 November 15
    - Junior colleges, 1950
    - Kagawa Military Government Team - Report on board of education, 1948 October 12
    - Kanto Bloc local superintendents' meeting, Urawa city office, undated
    - Kitatoshima technical school, outline of. Report, 1946 October 1
    - Kochi Military Government Team - Report on board of education, 1948 October 12
    - Korea - Education
      - 1945-1946
      - 1947-1950
      - undated
    - Korean schools
      - 1948
      - 1949-1951
    - Korean students, 1946-1951
    - Korean technicians in Japan, 1949 (Box 37)
    - Koryo secondary school - Outline of counseling. Report, 1951 October
    - Language reform - Recommendations by Lt. Com. R.K. Hall, 1945-1946
    - Language reform and simplification
      - 1945-1946
      - 1947
      - 1948
      - 1949-1951
      - undated
    - Language Simplification, Chapter VI (Box 38)
    - Language Study Commission, 1946 May - June
    - Laws pertaining to education in Japan, 1946-1950
    - Lewis, Dora S. (home economics consultant). Memo, 1947 September 7
    - Libraries
      - 1946-1949
      - 1950-1951
      - undated
    - Library Institute proposal, 1950 June 16
    - Lillo (Miguel) Foundation. Memoranda, 1949 August - September
    - List of physicians and hospitals acceptable to render medical care to non-occupation personnel, undated
    - Mailing list - Holiday greetings, 1950 November 24
    - Major Accomplishments of the Education Division, CIE, undated
    - Medical education, 1947
    - Memoranda and reports file
      - 1946 January - December
      - 1947 January - February (Box 39)
      - 1947 March
      - 1947 April
      - 1947 May - June
      - 1947 July
      - 1947 August - September
      - 1947 October
      - 1949 January - February
      - 1949 March - April
    - Military government
      - General, 1946-1950 (Box 40)
      - School inspection. Reports, 1946-1949
    - Ministry of Education
      - General
        - 1946
        - 1947-1950
      - Administrative Inspection Committee. Report, 1948 March
      - Administrative machinery, 1946
      - Chronological changes in organization, 1945-1949
      - Communications
        - 1946 May - 1948 July
        - 1948 August - 1949 March
        - 1949 March - December
        - 1950 January - May (Box 41)
        - 1950 May - July
        - 1950 August - November
        - 1950 December - 1951 March
        - 1951 April - June
        - 1951 July - September
        - 1951 September - December
      - Conferences
        - 1946 (Box 42)
        - 1947-1950
      - Decentralization, undated
      - Digests of the More Important Orders and Directives Issued since the End of the War, 1946 May 10
      - Digests of the More Important Orders and Directives Issued during October 1946, undated
      - Directives
        - Numerical guide to directives for 1945
        - Numerical guide to directives for January - April 1946
        - 1946 January - March
        - 1946 March - April
      - Establishment draft bill
        - 1948 (Box 43)
        - 1949
      - Laws, ordinances, etc., undated
      - Organization regulations, 1950 April
      - Organizational changes, 1949
      - Reports, 1945-1951
    - Mombusho communications. Index and synopsis, undated
    - Monthly summations
      - 1946 September - 1947 February
      - 1947 March - April
      - 1947 August
      - 1947 November
    - Nambara, Shigeru (President, Tokyo Imperial University) - Presentation of American periodicals, 1947 March
    - Nankitsu junior high school - The School Library Administration. Report, 1950 December (Box 44)
    - National and public teachers' status law. Draft, 1947 September 8
    - National Buddhist Students' Federation, undated
    - National Council - Recommendations on the board of education system. Memo, 1951 October 8
    - National Diet library - Report on Technical Processes, Bibliographical Services and General Organization, by Robert B. Downs, 1948
    - National Language Research Institute, proposal for the formation of. Memo, 1947 September 5
    - National Leaders Project, 1949-1950
    - National Public Service Law, 1947-1948
    - National Research Institute of Japan - New Education in Japan and its Problems. Report, 1950 January
    - Niigata prefecture - Schools and teachers cooperative associations, 1945-1946
    - Nippon Times article concerning Ministry of Education and teachers' union. Memo, 1947 July 26
    - Nugent, Lt. Col. D. R. Letter, to J. C. Trainor, 1947 October 4
    - On Universities, by Senroku Uehara. Translation of report, 1949 February 14
    - Organization and plans, undated
    - Organization guides, 1948-1950
    - Organizational charts, undated
    - Paper requirements. Memo, 1947 January 15
    - Parent Teachers Association (P.T.A.), 1948-1951
    - Partial revision of the Exceptional Law of Educational Public Service Officers, 1951 February
    - Personnel
      - General
        - 1946-1951
        - undated
      - Charts of Education Division, 1946-1950
      - Functions, 1948-1950
      - Job descriptions, 1949-1950 (Box 45)
      - Utilization survey, 1950
    - Physical education
      - 1943-1947
      - 1948-1951
    - Plans and projects
      - 1945
      - 1946
      - 1947
      - 1948
      - 1949
      - 1950
      - undated
    - Plans for fiscal year, 1951-1952 (Box 46)
    - Plans for fiscal year, 1952
    - Political education, 1947-1949
    - Possibility of the Emperor Being Considered a War Criminal, by Professor Del Re. Report, undated
    - Preparatory Committee for Curriculum Revision - List of members, undated
    - Press conferences and releases
      - 1945-1947
      - 1948-1950
    - Primer of Democracy
      - 1947-1950
      - undated
    - Private schools, 1946-1951
    - Problems confronting P.T.A.s in Tokyo, 1947 November
    - Professional associations, 1946-1951
    - Program for CIE Education Officers, undated
    - Project for out-of-school youth, 1951
    - Projects in the field, 1946 November
    - Proposed Amendments to Bill for Partial Amendments to Law for Special Regulations Concerning Educational Public Service, 1951 February - March
    - Provision of Teaching Materials, Chapter III
    - Public educational facilities
      - 1949 - 1950 May (Box 47)
      - 1950 July - September
    - Purging of government school personnel, 1946 December
    - Recent Developments in Japanese Education. Report, 1950
    - Reinstatement of purged educators, 1946-1951
    - Religion and education
      - 1945-1947
      - 1948-1952
      - undated
    - Reorganization and Expansion of Higher Education for the Preparation of Educational Personnel, Chapter XIII (Box 48)
    - Research board. Memo, 1948 September 13
    - Research Institute for Genetics (proposed), 1948 October - 1949 January
    - Research Memorandum to Parallel Division: Multifaculty Universities in Japan, 1948 January 24
    - Research Programs, Chapter XIX
    - Research requirements. Memo, 1947 April 10
    - Resolution relative to re-establishment of education. List of supporters, 1946 July 23
    - Responsibilities of board of education and school libraries. Minutes of meeting, 1948 November 22
    - Return/transfer of responsibilities to Japanese government agencies, 1949-1951
    - Rockefeller, John D. III, visit of August 1947
    - Rockefeller Foundation - Proposal, concerning the seminar in American studies in Japan., undated
    - Romaji experimental program, 1946-1951
    - Roster of Japanese Educational Institutions, 1947-1949
    - Ryukyuan students in Japan, 1949-1950
    - Saitama - Executive plan of public U.S.S. re-organization, 1950 January 26
    - Saitama prefecture
      - Board members, 1950 November
      - Educational administration, 1948-1951
      - Educational statistics as of April 1950
      - Public schools, undated (Box 49)
    - Salaries and Welfare of Educational Personnel, Chapter XI
    - School building needs. Report, 1949 September 6
    - School calendar in Japan, 1946 December 6
    - School education law, 1947 February 22
    - School establishment law, amendment of, circa 1950
    - School facilities, 1949-1951
    - School finance., 1945-1951
    - School Plant Facilities, Chapter X
    - Scholarships, 1950-1951
    - Scientific Advisory Group. Report, 1947-1948
    - Screening of educators
      - 1945-1947 (Box 50)
      - 1949-1950
    - Secondary education
      - 1946-1950
      - undated
    - Shintoism, by Professor Del Re. Report, undated
    - Six - three (6 - 3) education system, 1945-1947
    - Social education
      - 1945-1948
      - 1949-1950
    - Social studies, 1947
    - Staff list, undated
    - Staff meetings, 1946-1950 (Box 51)
    - Staff studies
      - 1945
      - 1946
      - undated
    - Staff visits to Okinawa and Ryukyu Islands, 1947-1949
    - Student activities, 1946-1951
    - Student Government in Japan, by D.M. Typer. Transcript of address, 1949 November 1
    - Student organizations, 1946-1949
    - Student political activities
      - 1949 March 15 - 1950 October 3
      - 1950 October 4 - 7
      - 1950 October 8 - 19 (Box 52)
    - Student political movements
      - General, 1946-1951
      - Press releases, 1950 October - 1951 February
    - Student rallies at Tokyo University. Memoranda, 1948 October (Box 53)
    - Student strikes, 1945-1951
    - Study of secondary school reorganization. Report, 1948 November 20
    - Suggestions for a plan for orientation of Ryukyus GARIOA students in the Ryukyus, undated
    - Survey of normal schools, 1946
    - Tax exemptions and discounts for youth organizations. Memo, 1951 November 5
    - Teacher certification, 1946-1951
    - Teacher education
      - 1945-1947
      - 1948-1951
      - undated
    - Teacher Education for Home Economics, by Dora S. Lewis (home economics consultant), undated (Box 54)
    - Teacher Ethics. Article, 1948 October
    - Teachers' manuals and lesson plans, 1946
    - Teachers' salaries. Memo, 1946 July 8
    - Teachers' Training Institute, 1944, 1948
    - Terminal Report, by L. Cronbach, 1947 May 3
    - Test booklet, Scholastic Aptitude Test, undated
    - Textbook and curriculum center, 1946-1951
    - Textbook authorization
      - 1945-1951
      - undated
    - Textbook revision, 1945-1951
    - Textbooks
      - General
        - 1945-1948
        - 1949-1951
        - undated
      - Compiling the elementary school Japanese reader (Box 55)
      - Excerpts from Japanese histories, undated
      - Japanese history courses, 1945-1950
      - Lists of texts, 1947-1950
      - Moral lessons in Japanese texts, 1941-1947
    - Three Years of Occupation. Report, 1948 August 20
    - Tokushima Military Government Team - Report on board of education, 1948 October 14
    - Tokushima Workshop, 1951 November 22 - 28
    - Tokyo Curriculum Conference, undated
    - Tottori Prefectural Board of Education - Condition of schools in the local districts suffering from the shortage of school rooms, undated (Box 56)
    - Training program in student counseling and guidance for Japanese university professors. Memo, 1951 February
    - Translation of History of Students' Ideological Movements, Chapter III, "The Proletarian Art Movement,", 1950 March 30
    - Translation program, 1947-1949
    - Undesignated schools, 1947-1949
    - UNESCO, 1948-1950
    - United Nations and UNESCO Movements, Chapter IV
    - U.S. Cultural Science Mission to Japan. Report, 1949 January
    - U.S. Department of State - USIE for Japan: Post- or Pre-Treaty Point of Departure. Report, undated
    - U.S. Education Exchange Survey - Report to SCAP. Tokyo, 1949 September 17
    - U.S. Education Mission to Japan. Committee of Japanese Educators
      - First Mission.
        - General
          - 1945
          - 1946 January 4 - March 13 (Box 57)
          - 1946 March 14 - 1947 August 19
        - List of names
        - Meetings and summaries, 1946-1947
        - Report, 1946 March 30
        - Tentative schedule, 1946 March 7 - 31 (Box 58)
      - Second Mission
        - General, 1950
        - Agenda, topics and attendants
        - Report to SCAP, Tokyo, 1950 September 22
      - undated
    - U.S. Military Government in Korea
      - Headquarters. Department of Education
        - Bureau of Higher Schools, 1947 January - February
        - Korean and American advisors. Memo, 1947 May 31
      - Korean Education Committee. Reports, 1946-1947
    - Universities. List, 1950
    - The University Curriculum and Related Topics, Chapter XVIII
    - The University Faculty and Student Body, Chapter XVII
    - University Guidance Programs, Historical Implications for. Report and memo, 1948 December 9
    - University law, 1948-1951 (Box 59)
    - University Reorganization and Restoration, Chapter XVI
    - Visiting consultants, 1947-1952
    - Vocational and Homemaking Education, Chapter V
    - Vocational Education
      - 1946-1949
      - 1950-1951
      - Special report on music education, undated
    - War-damaged schools, 1947 (Box 60)
    - Weaver, G. L. (vocational guidance consultant). Memo, 1948 July 29
    - Weekly bulletins, 1946 January - July
    - Weekly reports
      - 1946 January - March
      - 1946 April - June
      - 1946 July - August
      - 1946 August - November
      - 1946 November - December (Box 61)
      - 1947 January - February
      - 1947 March - May
      - 1947 June - August
      - 1947 September - October
      - 1947 November - December
      - 1948 January - March (Box 62)
      - 1948 April - June
      - 1948 July - August
      - 1948 September - October
      - 1948 November - December
      - 1949 January - February
      - 1949 March (Box 63)
      - 1949 April - May
      - 1949 June
      - 1949 July - August
      - 1949 September - October
      - 1949 November - December
      - 1950 January - February
      - 1950 March - April (Box 64)
      - 1950 May
      - 1950 June - July
      - 1950 August - September
      - 1950 October
      - 1950 November - December
      - 1951 January - February
      - 1951 March - May
    - Weekly summaries
      - 1945 October - 1946 July 13 (Box 65)
      - 1946 July 14 - August 30
      - 1946 August 31 - December 7
      - 1946 December 7 - 1947 March 1
      - 1947 March 1 - May 31
      - 1947 May 31 - October 18
      - 1947 October 19 - 1948 February 21
      - 1948 February 21 - May 29 (Box 66)
      - 1948 May 29 - July 10
    - What is Industrial Arts in the Elementary School? Article, 1948 November
    - Williams, Mrs., Diplomatic Section, Department of State, 1951 April - October
    - Women's education
      - 1945-1946
      - 1947-1949
      - undated
      - Lists of women's institutions, 1946-1947
    - Workshops in secondary education. Report, undated
    - World Organization of the Teaching Profession - Charter, 1951 October
    - Yamanashi Federated Education Association, 1948-1949
    - Yamanashi Military Government Team - Report on the Activities of Education Associations, 1948 July 10
    - Young Men's Christian Association, 1947-1948
    - Youth Organizations
      - 1945-1947 (Box 67)
      - 1948-1951
    - Youth Organizations, Chapter XV.
    - Zen Gaku Ren activities, 1949 August - September
    - Miscellaneous
      - 1945-1948
      - 1949-1951
      - undated
  - Education Division. Special Projects Branch
    - Directory of national education associations, 1951 (Box 68)
  - Information Division
    - SCAP. CIE Information Centers Directory, 1951 September
  - Library Division
    - Notes and documents pertaining to the surrender of Japan, 1943 December
  - Media Analysis Division
    - Prefectural press analyses, 1946 March - September
    - Press analyses, 1945 December - 1946 September
    - Publications analyses
      - 1946 January - May
      - 1946 June - September
      - 1948 August - October
  - Natural Resources Section
    - Mission and Organization of the Natural Resources Section. Report, 1947 April 1 (Box 69)
  - Public Opinion and Sociological Research Division
    - Japan: Some Psychological Perspectives, by Tsuneo Muramatsu, M.D. Article, draft, 1949 October 12
  - Research and Information Division
    - Advanced educational institutions in Japan. List, 1946 March 2
    - Books received from Education Division. List, 1949 September 28
    - Japan Educators' Union, Activities of. Special report, 1946 April
    - Japanese cultural organizations. List, 1946 April